Kieran Roberts

+353830841412

kieranroberts.dev github.com/kieran6roberts

kieranroberts6dev@gmail.com

Personal Statement

Hardworking and enthusiastic Software Engineer based in Ireland with almost 4 years worth of industry experience working with full-stack JavaScript. Possessing a passion for problem-solving and the knowledge of taking large scale projects from concept stage through development, testing, deployment, and iteration. Building fast, responsive, and accessible sites using modern technologies to solve real business problems.

Work Experience

Full-Stack Software Engineer, Hashnode, Remote

May 2021 - Present

- Working closely with a dynamic 6-12 person developer team writing code largely in TypeScript and React, tending to a +50k monthly active user base.
- Coordinating with a product manager and design team to deliver several key full-stack features for our popular blogs product. Contributing to a roughly 250% increase in new blogs created per month since joining the team.
- Spearheaded an end-to-end test setup for the frontend including a continuous integration pipeline using GitHub Actions that helped increase confidence in code and decrease the number of bugs.
- Assisted in building and maintaining an in-house UI library from scratch, coordinating with the design team to bring consistency and accessibility across the site UI/UX.
- Delivering key accessibility improvements to Hashnode including the blogs product and initiated developer standards with regards to accessibility through developer documentation.
- Regular code reviewer and feature tester to help find issues, suggest improvements, and maintain code standards.

Various short term roles, New Zealand

Apr 2019 - Oct 2020

 Spent almost two years travelling and working in New Zealand taking up various short term work. Roles included Maitre' D, wait staff, hostel receptionist, and more.

Customer Service/Cashier, Asda Walmart, United Kingdom,

June 2017- April 2019

- Customer service desk/ checkout operator colleague dealing with customer refunds and exchanges as well as queries, complaints, and the sale of age-restricted goods.
- Also possessing experience as the person in charge of overseeing the checkout/cashier department and rotation of colleagues.

Technical Skills

TypeScript (JavaScript) - React - Next.Js - Node.js - AWS services - GraphQL - Git - HTML - CSS - TailwindCSS - software testing - code review - continuous integration - accessibility - performance optimisation - technical and creative writing.

Key Skills

Problem solving

 Being part of an efficient developer team at Hashnode required quick evaluation of complex problems and the delivering of efficient solutions on a daily basis.

Communication & teamwork

• Direct and constant communication is a vital cog of working as part of a fully remote team. Not only communicating within the developer team, but over communication between departments was a necessity for everyone to be aligned.

Decision making

 Each day working at a fast paced startup is an opportunity to work closely with the design team and make informed choices in adjusting the user experience from physical testing, key data points, and feedback.

Time management

Working remote and delivering key features on schedule requires time discipline.

Achievements

- Open source contributor to DefinitelyTyped, providing type definitions for an existing package that was previously without types.
- More than 125k views on my developer blog with articles featured in various popular newsletters for topics such as software testing.

Education

Bangor University, Bangor, Wales, United Kingdom

Sep 2013 - May 2017

• Integrated Masters Degree in Electronic Engineering (MEng) with first-class honors.

Llangefni High School, Llangefni, Wales, United Kingdom

Sep 2006 - May 2013

3 A Level awards - Electronics (B), Maths (C) and Physics (D),
11 GCSE grades A* - B and Welsh Baccalaureate award provided by WJEC (Pass).

References

Available upon request.